Damon Sicore

1117 W. Jefferson Street Waxahachie TX, TX 75165 512-963-5126

damon@sicore.com
https://damon.sicore.com

ACHIEVEMENTS:

Produced 30 major releases of Firefox; World-record holder for Most Software Downloaded in a Single Day for Firefox 4; Est. Number of Users impacted: 5 billion people; Deployed one-billion Wikipedia instances on mobile devices in China in 2016; Built Mozilla engineering from 18 engineers to over 600; Formed teams and efforts and created Firefox for Android, the Rust Programming Language, WebGL, FirefoxOS, WebAssembly, and Mozilla Research. Formed performance team at Wikimedia and doubled the performance of Wikipedia for the world; Eliminated all Critical Security Bugs in Firefox. Successfully launched two cryptocurrencies: NEAR and Aleo which now have a combined market cap of over 16 billion USD.

CURRENT POSITION:

MONADIC.US - https://monadic.us. - 2016 to Present.

CEO – MONADIC.US is a professional services company providing expert Rust compiler and cryptography services. Our main product is snarkOps, a suite of tools to enable rapid development of zero-knowledge applications on decentralized networks. MONADIC.US is a core validator of the Aleo network, and our tools enabled Aleo to successfully launch their programmable zero-knowledge decentralized network with a current market cap of 6 billion USD.

EXPERIENCE:

Aleo, Inc. - January, 2021 to March, 2022.

Vice President of Engineering – Responsible for the development of the Aleo zero-knowledge cryptographic decentralized ledger engineering project. Responsible for Engineering and IT/Operations. https://aleo.org

NEAR Protocol, Inc. – January, 2020 to December 2020.

Vice President of Engineering – Responsible for the development of the NEAR Protocol decentralized ledger engineering project. Responsible for Infrastructure, Open Finance, and Ecosystem Engineering. https://near.org

Wikimedia Foundation, San Francisco, CA. - February 2015 to July 2015.

Vice President of Engineering, Head of Product - Promoted to Head of Product in addition to VP of Engineering. Responsible for the editing, reading, and mobile software product direction and planning for Wikimedia (Wikipedia and supporting projects).

Wikimedia Foundation, San Francisco, CA. - September 2014 to February 2015.

Vice President of Engineering—Responsible for Wikipedia Engineering, a team of 160 engineers developing the software, infrastructure, security, IT/Ops, Fundraising tech, and QA for Wikipedia.

Edmodo, Inc., San Mateo, CA. – March 2013 to June 2014.

Vice President of Engineering—Responsible for the engineering, security, IT/Ops, Support, and QA of Edmodo, an education and school-based social network with over 18 million users.

Mozilla Corporation, Mountain View, CA. - November 2010 to February 2013.

Vice President of Engineering—Built and led a team of over 600 open source software engineers, technical leads, managers, and directors developing the Firefox Web browser, the Mozilla open source platform, Firefox for Android, and FirefoxOS. Firefox has almost half a billion daily users, and my mission is to ensure choice and innovation—pushing the Web forward—by creating the best browser in the world.

Mozilla Corporation, Mountain View, CA. - January 2007 to November 2010.

Sr. Director of Platform Engineering– Joined Mozilla as a director in 2007 to lead a team 22 engineers. Expanded platform engineering to over 75 open source software engineers, technical leads, and managers to develop the Mozilla platform, consisting of several foundational subsystems on which many products are developed (e.g., Firefox, SeaMonkey, Thunderbird, etc.). Oversaw four teams, each with managers reporting directly to me: JavaScript, Layout, Content, and Graphics as well as contractors and direct reports. Responsible for driving releases, organizational development and structure, overall goal-setting, scheduling, management, hiring, and compensation activities for the Mozilla platform team. Most notable achievements so far is driving the platform for Firefox 3, 3.5, and 3.6 which is used by hundreds of millions of users on a daily basis. Drove the platform for Firefox 4.0, a major version of Firefox.

JBoss, Inc., Austin, TX. - December 2004 to January 2007,

Lead of JBoss Labs and Development Manager.

PROFESSIONAL KNOWLEDGE:

- Leadership Knowledge: Experienced executive capable of leading all aspects of a company especially engineering and product management. Organizational Development, Management Systems and Control (Project Management), Software Configuration Management, Organizational Behavior, Human Resource Management, and the Management Process. Professional leadership consultant and mentor.
- Primary Knowledge: Programming Languages, Logic and Functional Programming, Decentralized Computing, Cryptography and Zero-knowledge, Distributed Development Methodologies: Agile, Extreme Programming, etc., Operating Systems, Networks, and Software Engineering, Organizational Behavior, and Leadership.
- Additional Knowledge: Cryptography and digital security (encryption technologies), Embedded systems, peer-to-peer agents, blockchain theory and applications, JBoss AS Applied Architectures, System Administration (router and firewall configuration, Sendmail, ipchains, DNS/bind, Tripwire, Linux kernel, bash, sed, awk, backup and recovery, Samba, NFS, LDAP, PGP/gnupg, clustering and load-balancing, and general TCP/IP networking).
- Language Knowledge: Rust, JavaScript, Python, Ada, Java 15 yr., C++ 6 yr., C 8 yr. Pascal, Lisp, Fortran, Motorola 680x0 Assembly, IBM 370 Assembly, Numerous markup languages like HTML, SQL and PL/SQL.
- Teaching and Training: Professional Instructor of JBoss Application Server Advanced J2EE classes, and J2EE System Administration using JBoss. Instructor for Revision Control using Subversion classes.
- Specialized Technologies: All Java and J2EE Technologies: EJB3 (and 2.0) JSP, JMS, Transactions, JDBC, XML, JNDI, Servlets (Resin, JRun, JServ, Jakarta-Tomcat), AOP (Aspect Oriented Programming), XDoclet and attribute-oriented programming, CORBA (Visigenic, Orbix, and Sun implementations).
- Enterprise Servers: JBoss Application Server (used professionally since inception), JBoss Portal 2.x, Weblogic Application Servers, Weblogic Personalization/Commerce Server 3.51, Weblogic (5.1.0 and 4.5.1), ATG Dynamo, SilverStream, WebSphere, Orion.

Operating Systems Knowledge: UNIX (Linux, Darwin, Embedded Linux, FreeBSD, OpenBSD, Solaris, AIX, and HPUX), OS X, Windows XP/2K/NT/95, OS/2, Novell Netware, Vax/VMS, VM, Stratus VOS, MS-DOS.

Databases: NoSQL, Oracle, DB2 (Universal DB), PostgreSQL, MySQL, MS SQLServer, Sybase, and various embedded databases.

UML and Object-oriented Tools: Together (Control Center and Together), Rational Rose.

Webservers: Apache and iPlanet.

Special Purpose Hardware/Software: gcc, make, ANT, Visual C++, Subversion, CVS, Visual Source Safe, PVCS, XWindow, Apriori, TFX, LATFX. Maven.

EXPERIENCE, CONT.:

Transplace, Inc., Plano, TX. - December 2002 to December 2004,

Director of Change Management.

Creditland.com – August 1999 to August 2000

Sr. Software Architect.

Deloitte & Touche Consulting, DRT Systems -March 1999 to August 1999

Consultant.

ADAC Healthcare Information Systems - June 1996 to March 1999

Sr. Software Engineer.

CERTIFICATIONS:

Sun Certified Programmer for the Java 2 Platform.

EDUCATION:

Texas A&M University College Station, TX Bachelor of Computer Science with a minor in Management. May 1996

References Available Upon Request.